[
  {
    "skills": "expanded-form-up-to-100-000",
    "topic": "Place values and number sense",
    "question_text": "What is 72594 in expanded form?\n\n",
    "question_type": "Fill in the blank",
    "correct_answers": [
      "70000 + 2000 + 500 + 90 + 4",
      "7 x 10000 + 2 x 1000 + 5 x 100 + 9 x 10 + 4 x 1"
    ],
    "solution": "solve\nUse a place value chart:\n\n\nten\nthousands\n\t\nthousands\n\t\t\nhundreds\n\t\ntens\n\t\nones\n\n\n7\n\t\n2\n\t\t\n5\n\t\n9\n\t\n4\n\n7 ten thousands is 70000.\n2 thousands is 2000.\n5 hundreds is 500.\n9 tens is 90.\n4 ones is 4.\n\nThe number 72594 in expanded form is:\n\n\n70000 + 2000 + 500 + 90 + 4"
  },
  {
    "skills": "expanded-form-up-to-1-000-000",
    "topic": "Place values and number sense",
    "question_text": "What is 10000+8000+200+40+3 in standard form?",
    "question_type": "Fill in the blank",
    "correct_answers": [
      "18243"
    ],
    "solution": "solve\n10000 is 1 ten thousand.\n8000 is 8 thousands.\n200 is 2 hundreds.\n40 is 4 tens.\n3 is 3 ones.\nUse a place value chart.\nten-thousands\tthousands\thundreds\ttens\tones\n1\t8\n\n\t2\t4\t3\nThe number is 18243."
  },
  {
    "skills": "place-value-up-to-1-000-000",
    "topic": "Place values and number sense",
    "question_text": "What number has 2 thousands, 1 hundred, 7 tens and 6 ones?\n\n",
    "question_type": "Fill in the blank",
    "correct_answers": [
      "2176"
    ],
    "solution": "solve\nRemember the place values:\n\n\nthousands\n\t\t\nhundreds\n\t\ntens\n\t\nones\n\n\n2\n\t\t\n1\n\t\n7\n\t\n6\n\n\nThe number 2176 has 2 thousands, 1 hundred, 7 tens and 6 ones."
  },
  {
    "skills": "relationship-between-place-values",
    "topic": "Place values and number sense",
    "question_text": "Complete the sentence.\n600 is 10 times as much as .",
    "question_type": "Fill in the blank",
    "correct_answers": [
      "600 is 10 times as much as .60"
    ],
    "solution": "solve\nYou can use a place-value chart to find the missing number. Start with 600.\nhundreds\ttens\tones\n6\t0\t0\n600 is 6 hundreds. That is 10 times as much as 6 tens.\nhundreds\ttens\tones\n\t6\t0\n600 is 10 times as much as 60."
  },
  {
    "skills": "convert-between-place-values",
    "topic": "Place values and number sense",
    "question_text": "Solve:\n\n\n7 tens =  ones",
    "question_type": "Fill in the blank",
    "correct_answers": [
      "70"
    ],
    "solution": "solve\nNow work out how many ones you can make from 7 tens. Count by tens.\n\n7 tens = 70 ones"
  },
  {
    "skills": "word-names-for-numbers-up-to-1-000-000",
    "topic": "Place values and number sense",
    "question_text": "How do you write this number using digits?\n\n\none thousand four hundred thirty-five\n\n",
    "question_type": "Fill in the blank",
    "correct_answers": [
      "1435"
    ],
    "solution": "solve\nUse a place value chart:\n\n\nthousands\n\t\t\nhundreds\n\t\ntens\n\t\nones\n\n\n1\n\t\t\n4\n\t\n3\n\t\n5\n\n\nYou write one thousand four hundred thirty-five as 1435."
  },
  {
    "skills": "spell-word-names-for-numbers-up-to-100-000",
    "topic": "Place values and number sense",
    "question_text": "How do you write this number using words?\n\n\n202\n\n",
    "question_type": "Fill in the blank",
    "correct_answers": [
      "two hundred two"
    ],
    "solution": "solve\nRemember how to write numbers between 100 and 999. Be sure to spell each word correctly, and to put the hyphens and spaces in the right spots.\n\nFirst, write how many hundreds. Write: two hundred.\nThen, write the tens and the ones. Write: two.\n\nYou write 202 as two hundred two."
  },
  {
    "skills": "spell-word-names-for-numbers-up-to-1-000-000",
    "topic": "Place values and number sense",
    "question_text": "How do you write this number using words?\n\n\n703\n\n",
    "question_type": "Fill in the blank",
    "correct_answers": [
      "seven hundred three"
    ],
    "solution": "solve\nRemember how to write numbers between 100 and 999. Be sure to spell each word correctly, and to put the hyphens and spaces in the right spots.\n\nFirst, write how many hundreds. Write: seven hundred.\nThen, write the tens and the ones. Write: three.\n\nYou write 703 as seven hundred three."
  },
  {
    "skills": "whole-numbers-on-number-lines",
    "topic": "Place values and number sense",
    "question_text": "Type the missing number.\n\n\n704\n705\n706\n708",
    "image_tag": "Grade5_A.11",
    "question_type": "Fill in the blank",
    "correct_answers": [
      "707"
    ],
    "solution": "solve\nFind the number that comes between 706 and 708. You can start at 704 and count up.\n\n707 comes between 706 and 708.\n\n\n704\n705\n706\n707\n708"
  },
  {
    "skills": "roman-numerals",
    "topic": "Place values and number sense",
    "question_text": "What number does this Roman numeral represent?\n\n\nXVI\n\n",
    "question_type": "Fill in the blank",
    "correct_answers": [
      "16"
    ],
    "solution": "solve\nX\t\tVI\t\n10\t+\t(5+1)\t=16\n\nXVI represents 16."
  },
  {
    "skills": "rounding",
    "topic": "Place values and number sense",
    "question_text": "What is 294 rounded to the nearest hundred?\n\n",
    "question_type": "Fill in the blank",
    "correct_answers": [
      "300"
    ],
    "solution": "solve\nFirst, find the digit in the hundreds place. This is the place you want to round:\n\n\n294\n\n\nNow look one place to the right:\n\n\n294\n\n\n9 is greater than 5, so you will round up. First, replace all the digits to the right of the hundreds place by zeros:\n\n\n294\u2192200\n\n\nNow add 1 to the other part of the number:\n\n\n200\u2192300"
  },
  {
    "skills": "skip-counting-sequences",
    "topic": "Place values and number sense",
    "question_text": "Type the missing number in this sequence:\n\n\n108,110,,114,116",
    "question_type": "Fill in the blank",
    "correct_answers": [
      "112"
    ],
    "solution": "solve\nFirst, look for a pattern. Notice how each number is 2 more than the previous number:\n\n\n108,110,__,114,116\n\n\nTo make the pattern complete, the number 112 must go in the blank space."
  }
]